ChrisWarren

Muncie, IN (469) 364-4015 chris.warren.2019@gmail.com LinkedIn | GitHub | Website

Software Engineer

ABOUT ME

I've brought a lot of **value** with my **variety** of **skills** and **experience**. I've done lots of different things like serving in the **military** or having worked in other roles that have helped build my **character**, **drive**, and **perseverance**. I genuinely enjoy being in a **group** or working **individually** within **agile** or **traditional** environments.

EXPERIENCE

SwagCheck, Inc. United States (Remote)

React Native Developer

December 2021 - January 2022

My responsibilities included developing the SwagCheck app using multiple technologies including React Native.

MyCircle, Inc. United States (Remote)

Founder/Co-Owner CEO, CTO, CFO

July 2021 - Present

My responsibilities include building the site & app using React, Redux, & Typescript & React Native.

Avaaz Media, Inc. United States (Remote)

Full-Stack Developer (WordPress)

December 2020 - February 2021

My responsibilities included developing the website for The Brown Geeks and helping to convert the website from WordPress (PHP) to React.js

The Five Star Institute, United States (Dallas, TX)

Computer Repair Technician
Director of Technology

March 2013 - December 2013

My responsibilities included:

• The monitoring, construction, maintenance, and security of the network

TOOLS

- Android Studio
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Visual Studio Code

SOFT-SKILLS

- Communication
- Team Building
- Team Management
- Project Management
- Mentoring
- Teaching
- Motivation

LANGUAGES

- Django[®]
- HTML
- Java (Android®Development)
- Kotlin® (Android® Development)
- Python[®]
- React[®]
- React Native[®]

- Increasing the profitability of the company by making systems and procedures more efficient reducing waste spending, which resulted in an estimated 3-million-dollar increase during my time there.
- As well as raising membership in our realtor community from 1, 000 to 1, 600 from marketing, and saw a 25% increase in e-learning platform use.

St. Matthew's Churches, United States (Westlake, TX)

Web Designer Network Administrator/Security Desktop Software Engineer

July 2010 - November 2012

I was responsible for building the company's website (both intranet and internet), LAN & WAN using various technologies such as **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, **C#**, & **Java**.

• While with them, I wore many hats in a company of 7 people.

Freelance, United States (Various) **Solution Engineer**

January 2007 - Present

My responsibilities have included implementing **Desktop**, **Mobile**, & **Web** services for my clients which have included **Java** (**For Android**®), **Kotlin**®, **React Native**®, **JavaScript**, **MySQL**, **PostgreSQL**®, **Firebase**®, & **React**®.

United States Navy, United States (**San Diego, CA**) *Information Systems Technician (IT2)* **2**nd **Class**

July 1999 - December 2006

While an active member of the **United States Navy**, I served with distinction.

TECHNOLOGIES

- Bootstrap
- CSS
- Firebase
- Git
- Node.js
- PHP
- JavaScript
- REST APIs
- SASS
- SQL
- Tailwind
- TypeScript
- Unit Testing

OPERATING SYSTEMS (OSs)

- Linux
- macOS®
- Windows®

EDUCATION

Kenzie Academy

Indianapolis, IN (Remote)

Certificate

Front-End Web Development & Full-Stack Web Development

October 2019 - October 2020

San Diego State University San Diego, CA (Correspondence)

Computer Science Bachelor's Degree

August 2000 - June 2003

San Diego State University San Diego, CA (Correspondence)

Computer Science
Master's Degree

August 2003 - June 2006

Open-Source Contributions

- KDE (Remote)
- Kubuntu (Remote)

OTHER CERTIFICATES I'VE RECEIVED

- Responsive Web Design September 2019
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures October 2019

freeCodeCamp.org

- <u>Front-End Libraries</u> February 2020
- <u>Data Visualization</u> June 2020
- <u>Scientific Computing</u> <u>with Python</u> July 2020